(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
AMANE KANATA GRADUATION LIVE
「絶対的アイドル」
Amane Kanata Graduation LIVE
"THE ABSOLUTE IDOL"
ようこそ
Welcome!
誰でも分かります
Anyone can understand it.
すぐに…
Immediately...
絶対的アイドル
THE ABSOLUTE IDOL
出会えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you,
もう息が止まりそうだよ
it feels like my breath is stopping.
何を見ているの
What are you looking at?
どこまでも澄んだ瞳で
With those endlessly clear eyes.
二人だけが触れる
Where only the two of us can touch,
世界できっと
surely in this world,
全てが今始まるから
everything is starting now.
君に逢うために
That just to meet you,
生まれたこと伝えたいんだ
I was born—I want to tell you that.
粗野な風も 胸刺す視線も
The rough wind, and the gazes that pierce my chest,
全部
everything...
ヒリヒリする声になるのさ
...becomes a stinging voice.
ずっと君のそばに
Forever by your side.
濁りのない好きって気持ちは
This pure feeling of love,
振り返るものなんてない
has nothing to look back on.
二人きり
Just the two of us,
未来さえ飛べるんだ
we can fly even to the future.
La la la...
どこへ行くの 小さな
Where is it going, this small...
自分に涙 溢れるけど
...self, overflowing with tears, but...
走り出せる
I can start running.
もしもはぐれたら
If we get separated,
体ごと散ってみせる
I'll scatter my whole body to show you.
花びらたった一枚の
Just a single flower petal,
姿になって
becoming that form,
君の愛求めて旅するよ
I will travel seeking your love.
ずっと Love for you 君を抱きしめる
Always love for you, I'll embrace you.
汚されない好きって気持ちが
This undefiled feeling of love,
時を超えて呼び合う
calls out across time.
二人きり 未来へと
Just the two of us, to the future,
飛べたんだ
we could fly.
出会えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you,
もう息が止まりそうだよ
it feels like my breath is stopping.
つないだその手に
In that connected hand,
少し強くなれる気がする
I feel I can become a little stronger.
出会えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you,
もう息が止まりそうだよ
it feels like my breath is stopping.
明日も 未来も
Tomorrow, and the future too,
ただどうしようもなく 好きだよ
I just helplessly love you.
Oh-oh-oh...
いつか僕らの上をスレスレに通り過ぎていったあの飛行機を
That airplane that passed right over us that day,
不思議なくらいに覚えてる
I remember it strangely well,
意味もないのに なぜか
Even though there's no meaning to it, somehow.
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
On the night I cried from feeling worthless,
ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
I just wished to become stronger.
そのために必要な勇気を探し求めていた
I was searching for the courage I needed for that.
残酷な運命が定まってるとして
Even if a cruel fate is destined,
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
Even if it appears before me someday,
ただ一瞬
Just for a moment,
この一瞬 息ができるなら
If I can breathe for just this moment,
どうでもいいと思えた その心を
I felt like nothing else mattered. That heart...
もう一度 遠くへ行け
Go far away once more!
遠くへ行けと
Go far away!
僕の中で誰かが歌う
Someone is singing inside me.
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
So passionately that I can't help it.
いつだって目を腫らした
My eyes were always swollen,
君が二度と悲しまないように
So that you would never be sad again,
笑えるそんなヒーローになるための歌
A song to become a hero who can laugh.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign!
転がっていくストーリーを
Let this rolling story go on.
守りたいだなんて言えるほど
I'm not strong enough to say I want to protect you,
君が弱くはないの分かってた
I knew you weren't that weak.
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ
I was even weaker than that,
君が大事だったんだ
You were just so precious to me.
独りで生きてくんだなんてさ
"I'm going to live on my own."
口をついて叫んだあの日から
Since that day I blurted that out,
変わっていく僕を笑えない
I can't laugh at myself changing,
独りが怖い僕を
At myself who is scared of being alone.
蹴飛ばして噛み付いて
Kicking and biting,
息もできなくて
unable to even breathe,
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
Even if my noisy head and gut get all messed up.
衒いも外連も
Even the pretense and theatrics,
消えてしまうくらいに
to the point they disappear,
今は触っていたいんだ
I want to touch it right now,
君の心に
Touch your heart.
僕たちはきっといつか遠く離れた
We surely reached out far someday,
太陽にすら手が届いて
even reaching the sun,
夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
Let's seize the time before dawn and laugh.
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり
Dyed in that burning blue color,
おぼろげな街の向こうへ
towards the other side of the hazy city,
手をつないで走っていけるはずだ
we should be able to run hand in hand.
君と未来を盗み描く
Stealing and sketching the future with you,
ひねりのないストーリーを
a story with no twists.
カサブタだらけ荒くれた日々が
Those rough days covered in scabs,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
this worn-out present, whittled down,
君の言葉で蘇る
are revived by your words,
鮮やかにも現れていく
appearing so vividly.
蛹のままで眠る魂を
The soul sleeping inside the chrysalis,
食べかけのまま捨てたあの夢を
that dream thrown away half-eaten,
もう一度取り戻すよ
I'll take them back once more!
Oh-oh-oh...
もう一度 遠くへ行け
Go far away once more!
遠くへ行けと
Go far away!
僕の中で誰かが歌う
Someone is singing inside me.
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
So passionately that I can't help it.
いつだって目を腫らした
My eyes were always swollen,
君が二度と悲しまないように
So that you would never be sad again,
笑えるそんなヒーローになるための歌
A song to become a hero who can laugh.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign!
転がっていくストーリーを
Let this rolling story go on.
君と未来を盗み描く
Stealing and sketching the future with you,
ひねりのないストーリーを
a story with no twists.
考えたってわからないし
Even if I think about it, I don't understand.
青空の下、君を待った
I waited for you under the blue sky.
風が吹いた正午
At noon when the wind blew,
昼下がりを抜け出す想像
I imagined escaping the early afternoon.
ねぇ、これからどうなるんだろうね
Hey, I wonder what will happen from now on.
進め方教わらないんだよ
No one taught us how to proceed.
君の目を見た
I looked into your eyes.
何も言えず僕は歩いた
Saying nothing, I just walked.
考えたってわからないし
Even if I think about it, I don't understand.
青春なんてつまらないし
Youth is just boring.
辞めたはずのピアノ
The piano I was supposed to have quit,
机を弾く癖が抜けない
I can't stop the habit of playing on my desk.
ねぇ、将来何してるだろうね
Hey, I wonder what we'll be doing in the future.
音楽はしてないといいね
I hope I'm not doing music.
困らないでよ
Don't look so troubled.
心の中に...
Inside my heart...
たって全部
...all of it,
どうしても消えなかった
Just wouldn't disappear no matter what.
今更なんだからなぁ
It's too late for that now.
もう
Don't...
思い出すな
Don't remember it.
間違ってるんだよ
You've got it all wrong.
わかってないよ
You don't understand.
あんたら人間も
Not you people,
本当も愛も世界も苦しさも人生も
Not truth, love, the world, pain, or life.
どうでもいいよ
It doesn't matter anymore.
正しいかどうかが知りたいのだって
Even wanting to know if it's right,
防衛本能だ
Is just a defensive instinct.
考えたんだ
I thought about it.
あんたのせいだ
It's all your fault.
考えたってわからないが
I think about it, but I don't understand.
本当に年老いたくないんだ
I really don't want to get old.
いつか死んだらって
Thinking about dying someday,
思うだけで胸が空っぽになるんだ
Just the thought leaves my heart empty.
将来何してるだろうって
"What will I be doing in the future?"
大人になったらわかったよ
When I became an adult, I understood.
何もしてないさ
I'm not doing anything.
幸せな
Those with happy...
顔した人が憎いのは
...faces are hateful to me.
どう割り切ったらいいんだ
How am I supposed to accept this?
満たされない頭の奥の
Deep inside my unsatisfied mind...
化け物みたいだ
...it's like a monster.
劣等感
Inferiority complex.
間違ってないよな
I'm not wrong, am I?
何だかんだあんたら人間だ
After all is said and done, you're just humans.
愛も救いも優しさも根拠がないなんて
To say love, salvation, and kindness have no basis...
気味が悪いよ
...is just creepy.
ラブソングなんかが痛いのだって
Even finding love songs painful...
防衛本能だ
...is a defensive instinct.
どうでもいいか
Does it even matter?
あんたのせいだ
It's all your fault.
考えたってわからないし
Thinking about it doesn't help,
生きてるだけでも苦しいし
Just living is painful enough,
音楽とか儲からないし
Music doesn't make money anyway,
歌詞とか適当でもいいよ
Lyrics can be whatever.
どうでもいいんだ
I don't care anymore.
間違ってないだろ
I'm not wrong, right?
間違ってないよな
I'm not wrong, am I?
間違ってるんだよ
I'm actually wrong.
わかってるんだ
I know that.
あんたら人間も
You humans,
本当も愛も救いも優しさも人生も
Truth, love, salvation, kindness, life...
どうでもいいんだ
None of it matters.
正しい答えが言えないのだって
Being unable to give the right answer...
防衛本能だ
...is a defensive instinct.
どうでもいいや
Whatever.
あんたのせいだ
It's all your fault.
Ahhh...
僕だって信念があった
I had beliefs too, you know.
今じゃ塵みたいな想いだ
Now those feelings are just like dust.
何度でも君を書いた
I wrote about you again and again.
売れることこそがどうでもよかったんだ
I truly didn't care about selling.
本当だ
It's true.
本当なんだ
I really mean it.
昔はそうだった
That's how it used to be.
だから僕は
That's why I...
音楽を辞めた
...gave up on music.
今なんじゃない
Now is the time!
メラメラとたぎれ
Burn fiercely!
眠っているだけの正義
Justice that is merely sleeping.
こんな僕も
Even someone like me,
君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to be your hero!
La la la...
かっこいい君には
To the cool you,
僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
Thinking "I might be unreliable"...
そりゃそうだよな だって
Well that's only natural, because,
今もこうして迷ってる
Even now, I'm hesitating like this.
La la la... 手を取ってくれないか
La la la... Won't you take my hand?
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero.
今なんじゃない
Now is the time!
メラメラとたぎる
Burning fiercely!
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden even within me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, before I knew it, I was holding your hand.
一体全体
What in the world?
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going carrying all that burden?
ねえねえ待って
Hey, wait up.
僕にちょっと預けてみては
Why don't you let me carry some of it?
信じてばかりの僕と
With me, who just keeps believing...
どちらが正しいのかなんて
I don't think anyone knows...
誰にもわからないさ
...which side is truly right.
ラララララ
La la la la la
僕らだけの世界
A world belonging only to us.
ラララララ
La la la la la
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's all give and take.
ラララララ
La la la la la
補い合えた暁には
When we finally complete each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want us to dream the same dream.
君はかっこいいと
You were so cool,
苦しめてひとりぼっちにさせたのは
but I hurt you and left you all alone.
少し僕のせいなんだよな
That was partly my fault, wasn't it?
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what we need to face is reality.
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now is the time for me to save you.
抱えないで信じて
Don't bear it alone, believe in me,
頼ってほしいんだ
I want you to rely on me!
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる
Burning and flaring up,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
the justice hidden even within me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by a helpless impulse,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
look, I'm holding your hand before I knew it.
放っておけない
I can't leave you alone.
そんなに荷物を背負い込んで
Taking on so many burdens,
どこへ行くの
where are you going?
ほんのちょっと
Just a little bit,
僕にちょっと預けてみては？
why not entrust a little bit to me?
こんな僕も
Even someone like me,
君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to become your hero.
ラララララ ラララララ
La la la la la, la la la la la
ラララララララララ
La la la la la la la la la
ラララララララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la la, la la la la
ラララ ラララ ララララララララ
La la la, la la la, la la la la la la la la
ラララ
La la la
ララララララララ
La la la la la la la la
ララララ
La la la la
ララララララララ
La la la la la la la la
はーい！皆さん
Yes! Everyone!
とうとう始まってしまいました 天音かなた卒業ライブ！
It has finally started: the Amane Kanata Graduation LIVE!
ということでですね
And with that being said,
こちらハッシュタグが あの シャープ天音かなた卒業ライブで
the hashtag here is, um, #AmaneKanataGraduationLIVE,
ございますんで ぜひこちら よろしくお願いいたします
so please, I ask for your support with that.
一曲目に歌った『Mela!』は
The first song I sang, 'Mela!',
実は初配信で歌うか悩んでいた楽曲だったので
was actually a song I debated singing in my debut stream,
ここで歌えてすごくよかった
so I'm really glad I could sing it here.
ありがとう
Thank you.
小さい頃からね ヒロインよりヒーローになりたいっていう
Since I was little, I was the type who wanted to be a hero
タイプだったので
rather than a heroine,
そういった楽曲をたくさん歌わせていただきました
so I've been allowed to sing many songs like that.
次からは ありがとうねみんな
From here on... thank you everyone,
拍手もありがとう
thank you for the applause.
次からはロックで！
From here on, it's Rock!
感情をぶつけるような歌に挑戦しますんで
I'll challenge a song where I can slam my emotions...
ちょっとマイクがね
Wait, the mic is a bit...
挑戦しますんで
I'll challenge it!
聴いてください 『劣等上等』
Please listen: 'Rettou Joutou' (Bring It On).
Yeah!
Grow up!
Give up!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Inferiority, fine by me, BRING IT ON!
劣等上等
Inferiority, fine by me!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Inferiority, fine by me, BRING IT ON!
劣等上等 不眠日本
Inferiority, fine by me, sleepless Japan.
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Child-deceiving mathematica,
バレてんだってそんなのってプライドがない
it's obvious, you have no pride like that.
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
Acting like a splendid warning bell,
紙の刑罰ばっかでつまんない
it's boring with just paper punishments.
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Come on, make more mistakes, it's fine!
退屈に手をかけて
Lay your hands on the boredom.
ママ やっぱあたしは
Mama, after all, I...
こんなところじゃ終われない
...can't end in a place like this.
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I might go crazy.
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
Goodbye to make-believe and acting.
ずっとこのままなんてさ
Staying like this forever...
いらないよ
I don't need it!
だだだ あたし大人になる
I'm going to become an adult,
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて
tasting both the bitter and the sweet.
今 パパパ変わる時代
Now, the times are changing,
悪いことばっかじゃないでしょう
it's not all bad things, right?
過去も罪も罰も
The past, the sins, the punishments,
すべて飲み込んで
swallow them all,
愛で生き抜いてやりこうんだわ
and survive with love!
Yeah 挑発
Yeah, provocation.
あたしたちは No Doubt
We are No Doubt.
緑のアイツにばっか構ってんね
You're only paying attention to that green guy.
さあ Burn up いつまた
Come on, Burn up, when will we...
もらえる合格
...get a passing grade again?
赤ペンいれてよ どこがダメなんですか
Correct it with a red pen, what's wrong with it?
ちょっと　混む　劣等感
A little congested, inferiority complex.
散っても　いいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine even if we scatter?
冗談じゃない　ブラックジョーク
It's no joke, a black joke.
中指立てたくなるような
Like wanting to put up a middle finger,
事情ありすぎて指が足りねえ
Too many circumstances, I don't have enough fingers.
から　Hands up　アンバランサー
So hands up, unbalancer.
暫定　3, 2... Whatever
Provisional, 3, 2... Whatever.
まあ　まあ　まあ　なんか要らない
Well, well, well, I don't need anything.
欲しがります死ぬまでは
I'll want it until I die.
伸びた背丈　育った街に
Grown taller, to the town where I grew up,
投げキス　見せ場は此処から
A blowing kiss, the highlight starts here.
覚悟しとけよ
Be prepared.
ダンダン　ダ　僕ら
Gradually, we are,
オートマになれる感多
Feeling like we can become automatic,
目論見　大抵な日々
Scheming, mostly ordinary days.
タンタン　と　困り
Lightly, and troubled,
精神　刺激　誰より
Spirit, stimulation, more than anyone,
タフに　出来てんの
I'm made tough.
いつも
Always.
いつも　夢を
Always, dreaming,
見せて　捨てて
Showing it, throwing it away,
生きて　行きたい
I want to go on living.
現実に　唾吐く
Spitting on reality,
You are!
だって　だって　くだらない
Because, because it's worthless.
言葉っか　譲れない
Just words, I can't yield.
わかるか？　あたしの美学
Do you understand? My aesthetics.
このバカ正直な
This stupidly honest...
拳一つが
...single fist is...
一途なんです
Is earnest.
切り札
Trump card.
愚直なんです
It's foolishly honest.
がむしゃらに
Recklessly,
生きて行けよ
Go on living!
こんなもんじゃない
This isn't all I've got.
ダンダン　ダ　私
Gradually, I am,
オートマになれる
Becoming automatic.
酸いも　甘いも
Sour and sweet,
噛み分けて　今
Tasting them both now.
タンタン　交わる
Lightly, crossing,
未来は　子供
The future, a child,
騙し　大人の
Deceiving, adults'
まかるでしょ
It passes, doesn't it?
理解　回ってくれない
Understanding won't come around.
世界　涙　生き抜いて
World, tears, survive them.
じゃあ　音鳴らせ
So, play the sound!
ああ　やる時代！
Ah, the era to do it!
Hey hey hey hey!
それでは皆様　お先にバイバイ
Well then everyone, goodbye for now!
どうしてこんな事になったんだ
Why did it turn out like this?
誰も教えてくれないんだ
No one will tell me.
何が正義だ　何が犠牲だ
What is justice? What is sacrifice?
秩序はボクを裏切った
Order has betrayed me.
初めは小さな穴だったんだ
At first, it was a small hole.
居心地だけは良かったのにな
Even though it was the only comfortable place.
プロパガンダと　ノメアウ・ティア
Propaganda and Nomeau-Tia...
露わ次第に強大化した
...as it was revealed, it gradually grew gigantic.
相対と絶対のほんの水蒸気圧
Just the water vapor pressure of relative and absolute.
都合が良すぎた音ね
Sounds that were too convenient.
一つまた一つと未来は過去を召した
One by one, the future consumed the past.
65535のテトラと
With 65,535 tetras,
0次元の理想抱えていてもなお
Even while holding the ideal of zero dimensions,
一つまた一つとエラーは明日を消した
One by one, errors erased tomorrow.
ボクらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
イデアの波に飲まれるな
Don't be swallowed by the waves of Idea.
残された空間でボクは
In the remaining space, I...
迂闊に息さえ出来やしない
...can't even breathe carelessly.
ボクらの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
あるとど　エゴが交差する
Alte dos, egos intersect.
XYZしか愛せないボクは
I, who can only love XYZ,
何を信じて生きればいい？
What should I believe in to live?
ドット包囲網　若い括り
Dot siege network, a young category.
レジスターすら
Even the register...
おいっせ　そうさ
Heave-ho, that's right.
無言圧力　数の暴力
Silent pressure, violence of numbers.
鋼に打ち込めよと
Drive it into the steel!
僕の警笛
My alarm whistle,
肩越しに響く風景
Echoing over my shoulder in this scenery.
放る断末
The death agonies released,
アルカディアの鐘が鳴る日は
Will the day the bells of Arcadia ring...
降るのだろうか
...ever descend upon us?
僕らの 16bit Wars
Our 16bit Wars.
ついであの何にもまれるな
Don't get swallowed up by anything unintentionally.
残された
What was left behind,
空間で僕ら
in this space, we...
今日もぐうすり眠れやしない
Can't sleep soundly today either.
僕らの 16bit Wars
Our 16bit Wars.
あるととエゴが交錯する
Alt and Ego intersect.
Weak to the world
瓦礫の正規で僕は
In this century of rubble, I...
実情ブレやしない
Actually won't waver.
僕らの 16bit Wars
Our 16bit Wars.
世界を敵に回しても
Even if I turn the world into my enemy,
表現し得ない
It can't be expressed.
ものが溢れることが
That things are overflowing...
何より許せなかった
...is what I couldn't forgive more than anything.
僕らの 16bit Wars
Our 16bit Wars.
はい
Okay!
皆さんありがとうございます
Thank you, everyone!
ここにね
Right here...
何があると思います？
what do you think this is?
水
Water.
こ... 今回はあのー
Th... This time, um...
結構歌に集中するラインナップできてましたけども
I've come with a lineup that focuses quite a bit on singing,
トレンド一位ってのは本当ですかこれ
but is it true that we're trending #1?
嘘かもしれませんけれども
It might be a lie, though.
本当かな
I wonder if it's true?
ガチかも
Might be for real.
ありがとうみんな
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとう
Thank you.
かっこいいと言ってくれてるのを見ながら
While watching you guys say it's "cool,"
もうメガホンマイクが手からすっぽ抜けかけましたよ
the megaphone mic almost slipped right out of my hand!
本当に
Seriously.
焦ったわ
I was panicking.
ということでね、えーと
So, with that said, um...
何かに挑んでいく曲
songs about challenging something...
みたいなのが好きなので元々
...are what I've always liked, so,
『劣等上等』と
I sang 'Bring It On'...
『僕らの16bit Wars』を歌わせていただきました
...and 'Our 16bit Wars'.
ね、すごい大好きでかっこいい楽曲たちなので
They are really cool songs that I love so much,
ぜひぜひ原曲もチェックしてみてください
so please definitely check out the originals too!
ちょ、ちょっと待って！僕Vtuberなんで
Wa- wait a second! I'm a Vtuber, so,
着替えは何秒かかると思う？
how many seconds do you think changing clothes takes?
1秒だ！
One second!
ほれ
See?
すごいだろ
Amazing, right?
これがVtuberバーチャルアイドルね
This is a Vtuber virtual idol for you.
ではこのまま
Now then, just like this...
続けていくぞ！
let's keep going!
ローリンガールはいつまでも
Rolling Girl is always...
届かない夢見て
...dreaming unreachable dreams.
騒ぐ頭の中を
Stirring up the noise inside her head,
掻き回して、掻き回して
stirring it up, stirring it up.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
"No problem," were the words she murmured,
言葉は失われた
but those words were lost.
もう失敗、もう失敗
Another failure, another failure.
間違い探しに終われば、また、回るの！
Once the search for mistakes is over, she rolls again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
私は今日も転がります。
"I will roll again today too."
と、少女は言う
So the girl says,
少女は言う
the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
while playing meaning into her words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready?"
「まだですよ、
"Not just yet,
まだまだ先は見えないので。息を止めるの、今。」
the future is still invisible. So stop your breathing, now."
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time,
重なる声と声を
Mixing voices with overlapping voices,
混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて
blending them together, blending them together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
"No problem," I murmured.
言葉は西へ流れた
The words drifted away to the west.
どうなったって良いんだってさ
It doesn't matter what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと
I might as well make a mistake,
誘う、坂道
the slope invites me.
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time,
私をどうか転がして
please just let me roll.
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl says, the girl says,
無口に意味を重ねながら
layering meaning into silence!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready?"
「もう少し、もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと」
"Just a little more, I'll see something soon."
息を止めるの、今
Hold your breath, now.
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time,
「私は今日も転がります。」と
"I will roll again today."
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
playing meaning into words!
「もう良いかい？もう良いよ。
"Are you ready? I'm ready.
そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
You must be tired by now, right?"
息を止めるの、今
Hold your breath, now.
今度こそ生き返れない
I thought I couldn't come back to life
そう思った ベッドの中
this time, in my bed.
気付けばカーテンの隙間から
Before I knew it, through the gap in the curtains,
朝が焦りを教えた
the morning taught me impatience.
あぁ、生きてたと安堵
Ah, relief that I was alive.
あぁ、生きてしまったと絶望
Ah, despair that I ended up living.
まだやれるのか
Can I still do it?
まだやらなきゃなのか
Do I still have to do it?
いっそ無理やりも変えてしまえば
If I could just forcibly change it...
なんてね
Just kidding.
僕は元気です
I am fine.
そう言って今日も笑って
Saying that, I laugh again today.
心はガランドウです
My heart is empty.
大袈裟な音がする
It makes an exaggerated sound.
終末の鐘の音か
Is it the sound of the doomsday bell?
それでもこの声が
Even so, this voice,
それでもこの口が
even so, this mouth,
それでもこの喉が
even so, this throat...
千切れるくらい叫ぶよ
I'll scream until it tears apart.
この腕が
These arms,
真っ白なこの羽が
these pure white wings,
僕のこの命が
my life itself,
生きたいと歌ってる
is singing that it wants to live.
出来るなら愛されたい
If possible, I want to be loved.
許されたい ここに居たい 愛したい
I want to be forgiven, I want to be here, I want to love.
誰も見てない 夢を見るよ
I dream a dream that no one sees.
だから 僕を見てろよ
So, keep your eyes on me.
感情の捨て方はさ
To throw away emotions,
粗大ゴミのシールを貼る
just stick an oversized trash sticker on them.
本音はいつも強がりの裏
My true feelings are always behind my bravado.
潰れる音がするんだ
I hear the sound of them being crushed.
あぁ 気付かれなかった
Ah, nobody noticed.
あぁ 気付いて欲しかった
Ah, I wanted someone to notice.
それでも君が笑ってくれるなら
Even so, if you smile for me,
いっそ心を無くしてしまえば
I should just lose my heart entirely.
なんてね
Just kidding.
叶わないなんて
That it won't come true,
一瞬でも思ったら負けだ
if I think that for even a second, I lose.
叶わないなんて
That it won't come true,
一瞬でもよぎったら辞めな
if it crosses your mind for even a second, quit it.
何万の諦める理由があったとしても
Even if there are tens of thousands of reasons to give up,
ただ一つの勇気がその手の中に
there is just one courage in those hands.
それでもこの声が
Even so, this voice,
それでもこの口が
even so, this mouth,
それでもこの喉が
even so, this throat...
千切れるくらい叫ぶよ
I'll scream until it tears apart.
この腕が
These arms,
真っ白なこの羽が
these pure white wings,
僕のこの命が
my life itself,
生きたいと歌ってる
is singing that it wants to live.
出来るなら愛されたい
If possible, I want to be loved.
許されたい ここに居たい 愛したい
I want to be forgiven, I want to be here, I want to love.
誰も見てない 夢を見るよ
I dream a dream that no one sees.
だから 僕を見てろよ
So, keep your eyes on me.
誰も見ていない夢を見せるよ
I will show you a dream that no one sees.
だから 僕を信じて
So, believe in me.
はい！皆さん
Yes! Everyone!
今のは最後のオリジナル楽曲です
That was my final original song.
「誰も見ていない夢を見ろ」はね
'Dream a Dream No One Sees'...
本日24時にリリース！
Releases today at 24:00!
うわー！こちらのジャケットをですね
Whoa! Please use this jacket art...
頼りに探してくださいね 頼むよ
...as a guide to find it. I'm counting on you.
いや この曲あまりにも卒業ソングすぎるって思ったでしょう
You probably thought, 'This song is way too much like a graduation song,' right?
これ実は卒業決める前に作られていた曲で
Actually, this song was made before I even decided to graduate.
卒業決める前に あ MVは明日ね
Before I decided... Ah, the MV is out tomorrow.
明日の20時 もうかなたそがいなくなっても
Tomorrow at 20:00. Even if Kanata-so is gone...
予約投稿というものがある ネットには
...'scheduled upload' exists on the internet.
ということで明日の20時に投稿されるんですが
So it will be posted tomorrow at 20:00.
内容も実は 卒業誰も知らずに作っているということで
The content was actually made without anyone knowing about the graduation.
なんかこんな偶然の一致で それっぽくなってしまいました
It just ended up sounding like that by pure coincidence.
それを踏まえてまた なんでやねんと思いながら
Keeping that in mind, while thinking 'What the heck?'...
聴いてください ヒグチアイさんにね 作詞作曲していただいて
...please listen to it. Higuchi Ai-san wrote and composed it.
あの「悪魔の子」をね いっぱい歌ったりしたんで
I've sung 'Akuma no Ko' a lot...
超嬉しかったです ありがとうございます
...so I was super happy. Thank you very much.
そしてですね お次はグッズを紹介させていただきます
And next, I'd like to introduce the merchandise!
こちら！
Here!
はい 天音かなた卒業グッズがもう出てます
Yes, Amane Kanata Graduation Goods are already out!
なんと出てる！ということで それでは一つずつ見ていきましょう
Believe it or not, they're out! So, let's look at them one by one.
まずはこちら アクリルパネル！
First is this. Acrylic Panel!
はい アクリルパネルです かわいいでしょ
Yes, it's an Acrylic Panel. Cute, right?
じゃん！
Ta-da!
こちらね おしおママに想いをお伝えした上で
I conveyed my feelings to Oshio-mama for this...
描き下ろしていただいたイラストになっております
...and she drew this illustration for me.
ま 本当にね あの みんなに対して
Well, really... towards everyone...
最後は まあ笑顔かな とか
...I thought, 'In the end, it should be a smile.'
青い薔薇というものをね 最初からちょっとモチーフ的に
Also, the blue rose motif has been there since the beginning...
入れたりすることがあったので こちらでまた入れていただきました
...so I had her include it again here.
かわいいでしょ 笑顔にしてもらいました
Cute, right? She made me smile.
お次はこちら！
Next is this!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
かなた＆こなたのアクリルスタンドです
It's a Kanata & Konata Acrylic Stand!
これすごい これもね 僕がね本当にね
This is amazing. I really...
こなたという妹というものを ぜひこのように残して
...wanted to leave my little sister Konata behind in this form.
行きてぇよということで 僕が欲しいがために生まれたグッズでございます
It's a product born simply because *I* wanted it!
かわいいでしょ
Cute, isn't it?
エロいよな
It's kinda sexy, huh?
ということで 次はこちら！
So, next is this!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
ボイスキーホルダーです
Voice Keychain!
ボイスの6種は僕がオリジナル考えました
I came up with the 6 original voice lines myself.
オリジナルっつってもね 「へい！コーンかなた」とかだけ
Even if I say original, it's just stuff like 'Hey! Kon-Kanata!'
で このイラストもですね 僕 原案を描いて
And for this illustration, I drew the draft...
プロがすごいよくしてくれましたね
...and a pro made it look super good.
でもわかるでしょ かなたその絵柄って
But you can tell it's Kanata-so's style, right?
皆さんありがとうございますと
Thank you, everyone.
収録ボイスは届いてからのお楽しみです
The recorded voices are a surprise for when it arrives.
いっぱいポチポチしてください
Please click it lots.
そして最後のグッズはこちら！
And the final item is this!
じゃじゃーん！
Ja-jan!
あるてぃめっとへい民認定証！
The Ultimate Heimin Certificate!
これは最後まで応援してくれた究極のへい民
This is for the ultimate Heimin who supported me until the end.
アルティメットへい民の認定証です
A certificate for the Ultimate Heimin.
シリアルナンバーが入っていて世界で一枚です
It has a serial number, so it's the only one in the world.
ちなみにちょっと あの お買い得じゃねえや
By the way, it's kinda... not 'a bargain'...
手が届きやすいので これだけでもって
...but it's affordable. So even if you just get this...
ぜひ皆さん 思い出によろしくお願いします
...please keep it as a memory.
今までへい民じゃなかったけど 「かなたーん」て思った人もね
Even if you weren't a Heimin before, if you thought 'Kanata-an'...
アルティメットへい民だから アンタは
...you are an Ultimate Heimin too!
えー お次は こちら特典ですね
Err, next is... the bonus here.
はい 特典はポストカードになっております
Yes, the bonus is a postcard.
え 数量限定が直筆サイン入りだったんですが
The limited quantity version had a handwritten autograph...
こちらはですね 12月24日の8時から発売開始しており
...but sales started at 8:00 on December 24th...
もう品切れ ごめんなさい 完売しているんですけど
...and it's already sold out. Sorry, it's sold out.
フルセットの方はまだありますので
But the full set is still available.
箔押し複製サイン入ってますのでよろしくお願いします
It has a foil-stamped duplicate signature, so please check it out.
ちょっとね このフルセット特典の方は 「寂しいよ」っていう気持ちが
For this full set bonus, the feeling of 'I'm lonely'...
ちょっと溢れ出ちゃった感じになっております
...kind of overflowed a little bit.
はい ぜひよろしくお願いします
Yes, please treat it well.
ふう すげえ汗かいてきちゃった
Phew, I'm starting to sweat a lot.
サプライズ！
SURPRISE!
え？ なんだ なんだ？
Eh? What? What?
かなたー！
Kanata!
え？ やめてよ！
Eh? Stop it!
一人で辞めさせないよ
We won't let you quit alone!
来たよ！
We're here!
来ちゃった！
We came!
サプライズ！
Surprise!
来てるんですけど！
They're actually here!
え？ かなた！
Eh? Kanata!
聞いてないよ！
I didn't hear about this!
ひとりで辞めさせねえよ
We ain't letting you quit alone.
やだ！ ゲストいないので！
No! There are no guests!
いるよ！
We are here!
一人で辞めさせないよ
We won't let you quit alone!
寂しいだろ！
It'd be lonely, right?!
一人で辞めさせないよ
We won't let you quit alone!
来るよ！
We're coming!
うそ！
No way!
あんた達来てくれんの？
You guys came for me?
あ 出てる！ 出てる！
Ah, they're out! They're out!
ころさんとラミトワちゃんがなんか
Koro-san and Lamy-Towa-chan...
来てくれました！
...somehow came here!
え？
Eh?
ちょっと我々から渡したいものがありますよね？
We actually have something we want to give you, right?
何？何？マジで聞いてない、知らない！何？
What? What? I seriously haven't heard about this! I don't know! What?
マジで言ってない！マジで言ってない！
We seriously didn't tell you! We seriously didn't!
え、何！？
Eh, what is it?!
やだ、ちょっと...
Oh no, wait...
泣かせないでね、今！
Don't make me cry right now!
はい、どうぞー！
Here, go ahead!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
持てないか、持てないよね。
Can't hold it? You can't hold it, right.
あーすごい！
Ah, amazing!
これ3人で選んだ...
The three of us chose this...
花束？
A bouquet?
そう！
Yes!
お花です！
It's flowers!
え、すごい！なんかとても美しいバラみたいな感じの...
Eh, wow! It looks like very beautiful roses...
バーチャル空間には映らないんだけど...
It doesn't show up in this virtual space, but...
そう、ちょっと映んないんですけど...
Right, it doesn't really show up, but...
僕だけのものです、みんな。
It belongs only to me, everyone.
え、すごい！こんなにでかい花束もらったことない！
Eh, wow! I've never received such a huge bouquet!
じゃ一旦回収します。
Okay, we'll take it back for now.
あ、すいません。ありがとうございます。
Ah, sorry. Thank you.
それとね、3人で寄せ書きもして...
Also, the three of us wrote a message card together...
えー！
Ehh?!
しましたー！
We did!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
やだ、こんな今見たら泣いちゃう！
Oh no, if I look at it now, I'll cry!
じゃあ...
Then...
没収します！
We'll confiscate it!
また後でね！ありがとう！
Later then! Thank you!
みんな...え、待って待って、嫌だ、本当嫌だ！
Everyone... Eh, wait, wait, no! I really don't want this!
え、辞める？辞めるの？
Eh, are you quitting? Are you quitting?
ここね、ここがいいね！
Right here, this is a good spot!
ここで辞めて大団円をするんですけど...
We'll end it right here for a grand finale...
だっていいよね？
It's fine, right?
3人も背負ってくれるってことで一緒に...
Since the three of you will bear the burden together...
背負う、背負う！
We'll bear it, we'll bear it!
背負うよ！
We'll bear it!
心強！
So reassuring!
明日初配信しよ、明日初配信！
Let's do our debut stream tomorrow! Debut stream tomorrow!
明日ね、切り替えて初配信しよう！
Tomorrow, yeah, let's switch gears and do a debut stream!
切り替えていくか...いやもうありがとうみんな。
Switch gears, huh... No, really, thank you everyone.
もう嬉しい...！
I'm so happy...!
めちゃめちゃ頼んだの、会いに来たいって。
I really, really asked them to come see me.
そうなの！
That's right!
もう1人で、なんか勝手にいろんなもの背負ってさ！
She was taking on all sorts of burdens all by herself!
そうだよ！
Exactly!
辞めていくなんて許せない！逃さないと言ったから！
I won't forgive you if you quit! I said I wouldn't let you get away!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頼れよもっと！
Rely on us more!
周りを頼れ！
Rely on those around you!
頼れ頼れ！
Rely on us, rely on us!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
でもそこで、ちょっと無理を言って...
But still, I asked a bit of a selfish favor...
今日駆けつけさせていただきました！
And we rushed over here today!
本当に、本当に本当にすごいこと...
Really, it's truly, truly amazing...
本当にすごいこと...ありがとうね。
It's truly amazing... Thank you.
最後まで見るから！
We'll watch until the end!
見てるからね！
We'll be watching!
行っちゃうの？
Are you going?
行かない！お前が行くんだよ！
I'm not going! YOU are the one going!
お前が行くんだよ！
You're the one going!
先に引くんだ！行っちゃうの残念だなー！
We're stepping back first! Too bad you're going!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
行かない！見てるからね！
We're not leaving! We'll be watching!
ずっと見てるよ！ありがとう！
We'll be watching the whole time! Thank you!
頑張ってね！
Good luck!
最後まで！
Until the end!
まだ泣かないよ、まだあるからね。
I won't cry yet, there's still more to go.
まだあるもんね！
There's still more, right!
帰ってきてんのね、今本当にずっと。
It's all coming back to me right now, really.
頼むよ！ありがとう！
I'm counting on you! Thank you!
頑張れ！頑張ってね！
Do your best! Good luck!
ありがとうね、これからもずっと仲良くしてください。
Thank you, please let's be close friends forever.
当たり前だよ！
Of course!
一生友達だよね？
We're friends for life, right?
一生友達だよ！
Friends for life!
ずっと友達！
Friends forever!
ずっとこれからも先も！
Forever and ever, from now on too!
ずっとだからね！
Forever, okay!
当たり前だよ！
Of course!
縁側で語り明かそうね！
Let's chat all night on the porch!
おばあちゃんになってね...そこで見てるから！
When we become grandmas... We'll be watching from there!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頑張れ！
Do your best!
大好きだぞ！
I love you guys!
大好きだよ！
We love you!
愛してるよ！
I love you!
頑張ってね！ありがとう！
Good luck! Thank you!
またね！またね！
See you! See you!
またね！
See you!
ええ...
Ehh...
今回、あのみんなに説明した感じで...
This time, like I explained to everyone...
もうゲストはね、今回は呼べないけど...
I said I couldn't invite any guests this time...
勘弁よって言ってたんですけど...
I said, 'Please spare me'...
ころさんとあずちゃんとロボ子が来てくれました。
But Koro-san, Azu-chan, and Roboco came anyway.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much, truly.
あの...それでは！ここから！
Umm... Well then! From here on!
オリジナル楽曲が続いていきます。
We'll continue with original songs.
歌えるのはね、最後になってしまうんですが...
This will be the last time I can sing them, but...
だからこそ、たくさんの思い出を思い出しながら...
That's exactly why, while remembering all the memories...
心を込めて歌っていこうと思います。
I want to sing with all my heart.
ちょっと待って、びっくりした...
Wait a sec, I was surprised...
本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much.
もう本当に素晴らしい友達を持って幸せです。
I'm truly happy to have such wonderful friends.
ホロライブに入ってよかった。
I'm glad I joined Hololive.
ということでじゃあ！
So, with that said!
聴いてねー！
Please listen!
きゅーぴっど。
Cupid.
きみのキューピッドです　向かう夢中
I am your cupid, heading into a trance
きっと夢に出てくる　チュチュチュチュ
Surely I'll appear in your dreams, chu chu chu chu
チュチュチュチュ　チュチュチュチュ
Chu chu chu chu, chu chu chu chu
キュートひしめ天国
Cute packed heaven
インキャララバイ
Inca Lullaby
ついに鳴った着信音
The ringtone finally rang
やだやだやだやだ！
No no no no!
強制直帰の５時半
Forced to go home at 5:30
やだやだやだやだ！
No no no no!
誰か頑張ってるエレベーター
Someone's trying hard, elevator
やだやだやだやだ！
No no no no!
そう我らこそ陰の者
Yes, we are the gloomy ones
笑おう　笑おう　せめて笑おう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, let's at least laugh
あはは...無理...帰りたい...
Ahaha... I can't... I want to go home...
来ない　来ない　渇きまくり
Not coming, not coming, totally parched
反省　反省　また反省だ
Regret, regret, regret again
鏡ですらも恐ろしいんだ
Even mirrors are terrifying
明日は今日より
Tomorrow, more than today...
人間になりたい
I want to become human!
なりたーい！
I want to be one!
なりたーい！なりたーい！
I want to be one! I want to be one!
なりたーい！
I want to be one!
おやすみーさーん！
Good night Sun!
DA・LI・LA
DA-LI-LA
あなたに捧げるわ
I dedicate this to you,
私の愛とやらすべて
all of my so-called love.
この手は私を守る
These hands protect me,
そのためあったのね
that's what they were for.
雑踏に君と僕は
You and I in the crowd,
どんな作用だかご希望
what kind of effect do you desire?
ラストは運とかじゃないっけ
Isn't the ending just luck anyway?
ちょびっと痛いだけ
It just hurts a little bit.
チョイと少しだけ
Just a tiny bit.
誰も彼も綺麗
Everyone and everything is beautiful.
最初抜け出し死ぬ派手見なアッパレ
First to break out, die flashy, look at that, bravo.
重ねどれとどれ鉄砲
Stacking which and which gun.
天の采は投げられたのでしょ
The die has been cast by heaven, right?
作用作用どうも共倒れ
Action, action, thanks for the mutual destruction.
予防こそ隔離をこちらへおいで
Prevention is isolation, come over here.
鏡よその人だーれ
Mirror, who is that person?
恐れず僕と歌おう
Sing with me without fear.
パッパッパのパッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa-no-pa-pa-pa
巡り巡りよ 結局はどうしよう
Round and round, what should we do in the end?
そろそろ終わりにしないか
Shall we end it soon?
今ならば美しいほら
It's beautiful if we do it now, look.
あー
Ah...
君は今更戻れない
You can't go back now.
あー
Ah...
愛してくれ僕のことも
Love me, even me.
どうか邪魔などしないでくれ
Please don't get in my way.
遠い遠い別世界まで
To a far, far different world.
連れ去るままに幕が上がる
The curtain rises as I'm taken away.
ただまた会いたくて
I just want to see you again.
あなたにこの拍手を
Sending this applause to you.
無敵な愛 I I I
Invincible love, I I I.
聞かざれほらシークレット
Don't ask, look, it's a secret.
気持ち Tonight night night
Feeling Tonight, night, night.
意味ないじゃん
It's meaningless.
ガチShowtime
Serious Showtime.
かませ Clap
Strike a pose, Clap.
Unlock Unlock 妄想な
Unlock Unlock, it's a delusion.
傷つけたりしないで
Don't hurt me.
こんなバグだらけの世界になっちゃってごめんね
Sorry this world has become full of bugs.
大丈夫 安全圏に酔って
It's okay, get drunk on the safety zone.
安心な世界にコネ
A connection to a safe world.
見捨てないからずっと今日も
I won't abandon you, forever, today too.
Unlock Unlock 噛み締めて
Unlock Unlock, bite down on it.
ただ希望になれ
Just become hope.
合法的な善になるまで愛しあげるね
I'll love you until you become lawful good.
どんどん欲で満たして
Fill it up with more and more greed.
ぶくぶくに恋で肥やして
Fatten up bubbling with love.
忘れちゃうくらい
Enough to forget,
笑っちゃうくらい
enough to laugh.
ちゃんと Ai Ai Ai Love You
Properly, Ai Ai Ai Love You.
まずは息を吸え 音は立てるな
First, take a breath. Don't make a sound.
奴らに気づかれる前に
Before they notice us.
撃鉄を降ろし その時を待て
Lower the hammer and wait for the moment.
全ては一瞬のために
Everything is for this single moment.
手薬煉引いて 覚悟しろ
Wait eagerly and prepare yourself.
最後の一撃だ
This is the final blow.
怖気づくな 弱い自分だ
Don't get scared, it's just your weak self.
世界を変える起死回生 Aim at
Revival to change the world, aim at.
カリスマの目 アイドルの呼吸
Charismatic eyes, Idol's breathing.
ぜんぶ打ち抜けよ Last-resort
Shoot through everything, Last-resort.
鳥籠 ぶち壊して
Smash the birdcage.
壊滅の世界で
In this ruined world.
死に物狂いじゃ死にきれないなら
If a desperate struggle isn't enough to die,
刹那
in this moment,
泣くな
don't cry.
全てをこの一瞬にかけて放て Last-resort
Bet everything on this moment and fire, Last-resort.
僕の全てを込めて放つ Last-resort
Putting my all into it, I fire, Last-resort.
あなたがくれた希望で
With the hope you gave me,
約束の羽で
with the wings of promise,
今翔ばなくちゃ
I have to fly now.
共に往こう
Let's go together,
支配の先へ
beyond the control.
壊れるまで 戦うかい
Will you fight until you break?
今の僕は片翼でいい
Right now, one wing is enough for me.
翔べるよ 信じて
I can fly, believe it.
翔べるよ その先へ
I can fly, to what lies ahead.
遥か彼方 待って
Wait for the distant future.
永遠の
An eternal...
彼方まで
...distance.
Ah...
きっと組んで
Surely united,
手も...
our hands too...
世界で一番のアイドル
The World's Number One Idol
思い出して
Remember,
出会った日のこと
the day we met.
手を取って
Taking hands,
僕らの旅が始まった
our journey began.
走って転んで
Running and tripping,
涙を流しても
even if we shed tears.
気がつけばほら
Before we knew it, look,
顔合わせ笑う
we face each other and laugh.
喜ぶ声が嬉しくて
I'm so happy to hear your joyful voices,
夢が溢れ出すね
dreams are overflowing, aren't they?
君がいなきゃダメなんだ
It's no good without you.
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
Now, from the happiest idol in the world,
世界で一番の笑顔をあげちゃう
I'll give you the number one smile in the world.
僕を見つけてくれた
Because you found me,
愛してくれた だから
and loved me, so...
まだまだ終わらない
It's not over yet,
ちゃんとついてきて
follow me properly,
きらめく夢
into this sparkling dream.
羽ばたいてゆく
I watched the back
背中を見送った
that flew away.
雨上がり
After the rain,
君の傘を返したら
when I returned your umbrella,
手を引いて進もう
let's hold hands and move forward,
一緒にどこまでも
together forever.
気がつけばほら
Before I knew it, look,
また前を向ける
I can face forward again.
じゃれ合う言葉の中にも
Even in our playful words,
愛を感じています
I can feel the love.
僕じゃなきゃダメなんでしょ？
It has to be me, right?
でしょ？
Right?
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
Now, from the happiest idol in the world,
世界で一番のトキメキをあげちゃう
I'll give you the number one heart-throb in the world.
僕を支えてくれた
Because you supported me,
推してくれた だから
and cheered for me, so...
まだまだ終われない
It can't end yet,
隣にいてよ
stay by my side.
自信なんかない
I don't have confidence,
不安ばっかだ
it's just full of anxiety.
もう辞めようって
"Let's just quit,"
泣いた日もあった
there were days I cried saying that.
そんな時浮かんでくるの みんなの声が
At times like that, everyone's voices come to mind.
今までで一番諦めたくないの
More than ever, I don't want to give up.
ずっとなりたかった最強のアイドル
The strongest idol I always wanted to become.
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
Now, from the happiest idol in the world,
世界で一番の大好きをあげちゃう
I'll give you the number one "I love you" in the world.
些細な日常も
Even trivial daily life,
もっと大きなステージで
even on a bigger stage,
演じるも
even if I perform,
まだまだ終わらない
it's not over yet.
ありふれた奇跡を
I will tie these common miracles
君と結んでいく
together with you.
特者生存ワンダラダー！！
Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der!!
ハイ！ハイ！
Yes! Yes!
眩し！羨ましい！
Dazzling! I'm jealous!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
My retorts are sharp too, clear weather today!
騒？ボリューム？バキ？
Noise? Volume? Crack?
手にするぜ Big Mic
I'll get the Big Mic!
ガラクタ適当に頑張ろう (Oh Oh)
Let's do our best with this junk appropriately (Oh Oh)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
That's fine too, but
必死に頑張ろう (そうだ！)
let's do our best desperately (That's right!)
それが僕ららしいやな
That's just like us, isn't it?
なんだかんだそうやって
Somehow, just like that,
うんばばたち聞こえてる？決まってる？
Umbabas, can you hear me? Are you ready?
かなたちゃんドンドン全身全霊ちゃんと歓迎して
Kanata-chan is rapidly advancing, welcome me with all your heart!
高まるかい？ひそひそちゃんと強打して
Are you excited? Secretly, hit me hard.
興奮しよう
Let's get excited!
僕が呼んだもん 本当にするんだもん
I called for it, so I'll make it real!
現実超えろ未来 Ah
Surpass reality, future, Ah!
弱点も癖 スイッチでラッチャ
Even weaknesses are habits, flick the switch and release!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー
In other words, survival of the fittest Wonder-la-der!
楽しもう 面白がれること
Let's enjoy it, finding things to be amused by...
探し放題ですね
...is an all-you-can-search buffet!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer!
右左どっかじゃない
It's not right, left, or somewhere else!
聞きつけて一直線
Catch wind of it and go straight line!
つまり企んだら発車オーライだ
Basically, if you plotted it, it's safe to depart!
ワクワク寸前 Sha!
Excitement on the verge, Sha!
聞いて！
Listen!
みんなと離れるのが寂しいのと
I'm lonely about parting with everyone and...
楽器の血行が立ち直ってません！
...my instrument's circulation hasn't recovered!
僕をアイドルにしてくれてみんな本当にありがとう！
Thank you everyone for making me an idol!
なんなんだよ そんなこと
What the heck is that about?
言っちゃだめだ おバカ
Don't say that, you dummy.
わぁすごい ありがとう
Wow, amazing, thank you!
日々是装填でGo My Way
Every day is loading up, Go My Way.
虎視眈々でいたいだもん
I want to be vigilant like a tiger.
だって意気昂々がいいんだもん
Because being in high spirits is good!
全方位でガッツリ汗をかいてら
Sweating buckets in all directions!
Cha!
言っても心はちゃんと純粋で
Even if I say that, my heart is properly pure.
一体何個 軋マタイ不審で
How many creaking suspicions on earth?
一切合切 言い聞かせるんだ
I'll tell myself absolutely everything.
調子に乗ったら
If I get carried away...
すぐ飽きられちゃうから Ah
...you'll get tired of me right away, Ah!
解答なら程々こいで捨て
If it's an answer, row moderately and discard it!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー
In other words, survival of the fittest Wonder-la-der!
しがみつけ 努力と
Cling on to effort!
最後まで諦めないこと メモっておいて
Take a note: don't give up until the very end.
本当はBaby 自信がないよ
Actually Baby, I have no confidence.
本当はBaby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだって
Actually Baby, I'm just anxious and feel like crying.
でもねBaby くじけないって決めたの
But you know Baby, I decided I won't be discouraged.
だからBaby
So Baby...
挑戦したいよ 未開の天地
...I want to challenge the unexplored lands!
無限のフィールドで
In this infinite field!
いけー！
Go!
全身全霊ちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome me properly with all your heart and soul!
高まるかい？ひそひそちゃんと強打して
Are you excited? Secretly, hit me hard.
興奮しよう 僕が呼んだもん
Let's get excited! I called for it,
本当にするんだもん
...so I'll make it real!
現実超えろ未来 Ah
Surpass reality, future, Ah!
弱点も癖 スイッチでラッチャ
Even weaknesses are habits, flick the switch and release!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー
In other words, survival of the fittest Wonder-la-der!
楽しもう 面白がれること
Let's enjoy it, finding things to be amused by...
探し放題ですね
...is an all-you-can-search buffet!
無限のフィールドで
In the infinite field!
タイミングしなくてもいい
You don't even have to time it!
ど真ん中一直線
Dead center, straight line!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer!
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Be proud! The meaning of living in the now...
明日も明後日も確かめ進め
...confirm it tomorrow and the day after, and advance!
笑え！
Smile!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みんな！
Everyone!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい。
Yes.
え、聴いていただいたのはオリ曲メドレー。
Uh, what you just heard was an original song medley.
メドレーにしました。繋ぎましたよ。
I made it a medley. I connected them.
そして「世界で一番のアイドル」、作詞をしました。
And "The World's #1 Idol", I wrote the lyrics for it.
この時は卒業なんて考えてなかったから...
At that time, I wasn't thinking about graduation at all...
本当に... あの、いっぱい聴いてほしい曲です。
Really... um, it's a song I want you to listen to a lot.
そして「特者生存ワンダラダー!!」でした。
And that was "Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der!!".
はい、これは初めて... 出したね？
Yes, this is the first time... I've put this out, right?
オリジナル楽曲ですけれども...
It's an original song, but...
ちょっと語りたいこといっぱいあるんですけど...
I have a lot I want to talk about regarding it...
やっぱあの服だよね？ってことで...
But it's gotta be that outfit, right? So...
一秒着替えしてきました。
I did a one-second outfit change.
はい！やっぱこれだよねみんな。
Yes! It's definitely this one, everyone.
へい！こんかなた〜！
Hey! Kon-Kanata!
キャッチコピーは握力50キロ、ぎゅうぎゅう握り潰しちゃうぞ。
My catchphrase is: Grip strength 50kg, I'll crush you tight.
ホロライブ4期生、かなたんこと天音かなたです。
Hololive 4th Generation, Amane Kanata also known as Kanatan.
はい。ということでね、ろ...
Yes. So with that said, Ro...
危ないことはね、危ない橋は渡らないでおきまして。
Let's not do anything dangerous, let's not cross any dangerous bridges.
いうようなね、あの、感じでいきたいと思うんですけれども...
I think I want to proceed with... that kind of vibe, but...
もう本当にオリジナル楽曲はね...
Really, regarding the original songs...
たくさん聴いてくれたおかげと言いますか
I guess I should say it's thanks to you listening so much,
本当にありがとうございます 思っています
but I truly thank you. I really mean it.
みんなね あの この後ですね あの 22時10分から最後の歌ってみた...
Everyone... um... after this, at 22:10, the final cover video...
みんなと約束してました
I promised you all.
あの動画消えちゃって 歌い直そうって言っていたね あのKINGを
Since that video disappeared and I said I'd resing it... that 'King'...
投稿するので 絶対見てくださいね！
I'm uploading it, so please definitely watch it!
毎日一緒にいてくれたへい民
To the Heimin who were with me every day,
ホロライブの大好きなメンバーたち
my beloved Hololive members,
そしてたくさん支えてくださった 本当にお世話になった方々
and to everyone who supported me and took such good care of me,
全ての方に感謝しています
I am grateful to all of you.
夢のような時間は本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much for this dream-like time.
心... くちゅ... ここで噛むんね
My hear... *sniffle*... I stutter here, don't I?
子供の頃のアイドルになりたいという夢も
My childhood dream of becoming an idol,
作詞作曲をしてみたいという夢も 叶いました
and my dream of trying songwriting and composing, both came true.
そして 最後の曲ですが まだ歌うんですよ
And now, for the final song... I'm still going to sing, you know!
僕が初めて作詞作曲した楽曲があります
There is a song I wrote and composed for the first time.
今はいない同期 ココの卒業に合わせて
Matching the graduation of my genmate Coco, who isn't here now,
4期生のトワ ルーナ わために捧げた楽曲です
it's a song I dedicated to 4th Gen's Towa, Luna, and Watame.
前を向いて 笑顔で
Looking forward, with a smile,
この楽曲で活動を最後にしたいと思います
I want to make this song the finale of my activities.
それでは聴いてください 「キセキ結び」
Please listen. 'Kiseki Musubi' (Miracle Knot).
約束しようよ
Let's make a promise.
僕ら出逢えた奇跡
The miracle that we met,
忘れないように
so that we never forget it.
夢抱いて集う
Gathering with dreams in our hearts,
青春アニメみたいな
just like a coming-of-age anime.
ハッピーなエンドになるかな
Will it have a happy ending?
耐え飛ぶよ
I'll endure and fly.
寝惚け眼欠伸して
Yawning with sleepy eyes,
今日は何をしようか
'What shall we do today?'
永久に続く海を駆ける
Running across the sea that lasts forever.
今は溜息
Right now, rather than sighs,
よりも勇気を
I need courage.
諦めるなんてないの
Giving up is not an option.
ここで歌う
I sing here.
僕の声は聴こえてますか
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
Let it reach you.
学校の友達じゃ きっとない出会いだった
It was an encounter that surely wouldn't happen as school friends.
画面の先の遥か遠くまで
Far beyond the screen, to the distance.
ささくれた言葉も 誰かの笑顔になる
Even harsh words can turn into someone's smile.
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ軌跡
With our own colors, the path connecting stars.
キラキラ輝くステージに 連れてくよ
I'll take you to the sparkling, shining stage.
泣いて笑ってはしゃいで
Crying, laughing, having fun,
毎日ジェットコースター
every day is a roller coaster.
たまには寝転んで お昼寝しよう
Sometimes, let's lie down and take a nap.
ちょっと自信ないとき
When you lack a little confidence,
ことりってデュエットして
I'll tweet and duet with you.
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと 許してね
Please forgive me for crying just for today.
未来の僕が
The future me
アルバム開く
opens the album.
傷ついた写真だって 宝物だ
Even the damaged photos are treasures.
僕の愛が見えていますか
Can you see my love?
君に届け
Let it reach you.
過去も喝采も 性格も違うけれど
Though our pasts, cheers, and personalities are different,
弱気なときは瞼 ぎゅっと瞑り
when you're feeling weak, squeeze your eyelids shut.
もう一回 もう一回 絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, I absolutely won't give up.
前の背中追う ヘッポコな僕でも
Chasing the back in front of me, even if I'm clumsy,
君の隣に居たくて 走るの
I run because I want to be by your side.
誰にも言えずに
Without being able to tell anyone,
描いた夢が 例え叶わないとしても
even if the dreams I drew don't come true,
ボロボロの靴でも
even with worn-out shoes,
カッコよくなくても
even if it's not cool,
あの日の僕ならなんて言う？
what would the 'me' from that day say?
止まらないで
'Don't stop.'
初めて僕ら出逢った日
The day we first met,
まるで昨日みたいに思い出すけど
I remember it like it was yesterday, but
もう行こうか
shall we go now?
最後に今 重なる奇跡
Now, at the end, the overlapping miracles.
僕の声は聴こえてますか
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
Let it reach you.
黒板のメッセージ 桜の風
The message on the blackboard, the cherry blossom wind...
声を聴いて
Listen to my voice.
ずっとずっと
Forever and ever,
嬉しい日 楽しい日
through happy days and fun days,
悲しい日
sad days,
別れの日も
and even days of parting.
それぞれの色で
With our own respective colors,
星結ぶキセキ
a miracle connecting the stars.
キラキラ輝くステージで
On this sparkling, shining stage,
約束しよう
let's make a promise.
いつかここで
Someday, right here,
また会おう
let's meet again.
あー、ありがとう！
Ah, thank you!
ホロライブに咲く アイドルの天音かなたでした！
This was Hololive's blooming idol, Amane Kanata!
6年間、本当に幸せな日々でした！
These 6 years were truly happy days!
こんな不器用な僕を 応援してくれてありがとう
Thank you for supporting someone as clumsy as me.
ずっとずっと大好きだよ
I love you all, forever and ever.
ずっとずっと家族だよ
We are family, forever and ever.
みんな本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much!
ありがとう
Thank you.